<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://adrianba.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://adrianba.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-16T13:37:29-08:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/feed.xml</id><title type="html">adrianba.net</title><subtitle>On land, on sea, and in the ether.</subtitle><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><entry><title type="html">Who can sue a company under the CCPA?</title><link href="https://adrianba.net/2019/11/16/who-can-sue-companies-ccpa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who can sue a company under the CCPA?" /><published>2019-11-16T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-16T10:53:00-08:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/2019/11/16/who-can-sue-companies-ccpa</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adrianba.net/2019/11/16/who-can-sue-companies-ccpa/">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jdsupra.com/legalnews/ccpa-privacy-faqs-can-a-company-be-sued-80335&quot;&gt;an article on JD Supra&lt;/a&gt; answering the question “Can a
company be sued under the CCPA for failing to post a ‘do not sell my personal
information’ link?” To my surprise, the answer given was “No.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analysis in the post actually addressed the question of whether a consumer
could sue a company for failing to post the link, but it did not address who
else might have a cause of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-can-sue-under-the-ccpa&quot;&gt;Who can sue under the CCPA?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/codes_displaySection.xhtml?lawCode=CIV&amp;amp;sectionNum=1798.150.&quot;&gt;§1798.150&lt;/a&gt; of the CCPA provides a cause of action for a data breach involving
disclosure of a consumer’s personal information because of a business’s
failure to implement reasonable security measures. This section allows
consumers to sue the business for damages after giving the business notice
and a chance to cure the issue if that is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/codes_displaySection.xhtml?lawCode=CIV&amp;amp;sectionNum=1798.155.&quot;&gt;§1798.155&lt;/a&gt; of the CCPA allows the California Attorney
General to bring a civil action against a business.
This action can be brought for any violation of
the CCPA including a failure to post a ‘do not sell my personal information’
link if the business is required to provide one. Just like in the data breach
case, businesses have a chance to cure the issue after being notified of a
potential violation before an action can be commenced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;public-vs-private-causes-of-action&quot;&gt;Public vs. Private Causes of Action&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is a higher chance of being sued under a law that provides a
private cause of action, which allows anybody who is injured to sue you, than
there is under a public cause of action, which requires a public body such as
the state Attorney General to sue you. Government agencies only have so many
resources and they need to prioritize where they focus their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, it seems irresponsible to suggest that a company cannot be sued
if they fail to post the required ‘do not sell my personal information’ link.
Depending upon the nature of the company, the type of information collected,
and the way in which it is being sold, a business might attract the attention
of the AG, and the penalties for intentionally violating the CCPA could be
large (up to $7,500 per violation, which could be per consumer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CCPA comes into effect on January 1, 2020 and businesses that sell
personal information should provide a “clear and conspicuous link” titled
“Do Not Sell My Personal Information” on the homepage that California
consumers will see (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/codes_displaySection.xhtml?lawCode=CIV&amp;amp;sectionNum=1798.135.&quot;&gt;§1798.135&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: the information included here is provided AS IS for discussion purposes only. It may not be completely accurate, may not be applicable in all situations, and should not be acted upon without specific legal advice based on particular situations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><summary type="html">Yesterday, I read an article on JD Supra answering the question “Can a company be sued under the CCPA for failing to post a ‘do not sell my personal information’ link?” To my surprise, the answer given was “No.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Particle Printable Buffer Library</title><link href="https://adrianba.net/2017/12/19/particle-printable-buffer-library/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Particle Printable Buffer Library" /><published>2017-12-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-10-19T12:31:00-07:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/2017/12/19/particle-printable-buffer-library</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adrianba.net/2017/12/19/particle-printable-buffer-library/">&lt;p&gt;Based on the code used internally by the Particle firmware for printing
to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; objects (see &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;StringPrintableHelper&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spark/firmware/blob/89f8e270ce7d748a4d9d5f633a650b0bacb728da/wiring/src/spark_wiring_string.cpp#L787&quot;&gt;wiring/src/spark_wiring_string.cpp&lt;/a&gt;), I have written a small
library that allows printing into a simple buffer. This avoids the reallocation of memory that occurs when using the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/adrianba/printable-buffer&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and I’ve published it to the Particle
library list so you can add it through the IDE or by use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;particle library add printable-buffer&lt;/code&gt; using the CLI.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><summary type="html">Based on the code used internally by the Particle firmware for printing to String objects (see StringPrintableHelper in wiring/src/spark_wiring_string.cpp), I have written a small library that allows printing into a simple buffer. This avoids the reallocation of memory that occurs when using the String class.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fix Surface Type Cover after firmware update</title><link href="https://adrianba.net/2017/12/15/fix-surface-type-cover-after-firmware-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fix Surface Type Cover after firmware update" /><published>2017-12-15T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-15T12:53:00-08:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/2017/12/15/fix-surface-type-cover-after-firmware-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adrianba.net/2017/12/15/fix-surface-type-cover-after-firmware-update/">&lt;p&gt;This week there were Surface Pro 4 firmware updates as part of the Patch Tuesday updates. After
the system updates completed on my SP4, the type cover stopped working. The backlight didn’t work
and the Surface didn’t recognise the keyboard being removed or plugged back in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reaching out to people here at Microsoft, I learned that you can make some internal systems
within the Surface reset by holding down the power button and volume up button at the same time for
about 20 seconds. That reset got my keyboard working again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen a few forum posts where other people ran into this issue but no clear message about how
to fix it, so hopefully if you run into the issue then you’ll find your way to this post with a
solution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><summary type="html">This week there were Surface Pro 4 firmware updates as part of the Patch Tuesday updates. After the system updates completed on my SP4, the type cover stopped working. The backlight didn’t work and the Surface didn’t recognise the keyboard being removed or plugged back in.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting the inactivity timeout in Windows</title><link href="https://adrianba.net/2017/11/29/inactivity-timeout/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting the inactivity timeout in Windows" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T15:02:00-08:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/2017/11/29/inactivity-timeout</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adrianba.net/2017/11/29/inactivity-timeout/">&lt;p&gt;Windows has a timeout that can return you to the lock screen after a period of inactivity. This
is useful if you want to make sure the PC gets locked if you walk away but don’t want to use a
screen saver and don’t want the PC to go to sleep. It is easy through the normal settings app to
configure the latter two cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To configure the inactivity timeout, you need to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gpedit.msc&lt;/code&gt; and navigate to the Security
Options folder shown in this screen grab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/uploads/2017/inactivity-timeout.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/uploads/2017/inactivity-timeout.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Local Group Policy Editor showing the Computer Configuration - Windows Settings -
Security Settings - Local Policies - Security Options node&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policy you need is called “Interactive login: Machine inactivity limit”. Double-click on this
and you can configure a timeout in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><summary type="html">Windows has a timeout that can return you to the lock screen after a period of inactivity. This is useful if you want to make sure the PC gets locked if you walk away but don’t want to use a screen saver and don’t want the PC to go to sleep. It is easy through the normal settings app to configure the latter two cases.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Samsung Smart Switch - How to install on Windows 10</title><link href="https://adrianba.net/2017/10/13/samsung-smart-switch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Samsung Smart Switch - How to install on Windows 10" /><published>2017-10-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-13T15:18:00-07:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/2017/10/13/samsung-smart-switch</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adrianba.net/2017/10/13/samsung-smart-switch/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samsung Smart Switch&lt;/strong&gt; is a tool that will backup your phone and transfer the data to a new Samsung
phone. You also use it to backup your phone to your PC in case you need to restore it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/uploads/2017/samsung-smart-switch.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/uploads/2017/samsung-smart-switch.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Samsung Smart Switch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.samsung.com/us/support/answer/ANS00048603/&quot;&gt;Samsung Smart Switch for Mac or PC&lt;/a&gt;
on the Samsung site. The PC version has a dependency on some relatively old versions of the Visual
C++ runtime, which you may not have installed on a newer PC running Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to install both the x86 and x64 versions of the runtime:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=5582&quot;&gt;Microsoft Visual C++ 2008 SP1 Redistributable Package (x86)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=2092&quot;&gt;Microsoft Visual C++ 2008 SP1 Redistributable Package (x64)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had managed to install enough apps on my phone that some of them
were causing some performance problems (one of the challenges
I’ve found with Android). I had decided to back-up my phone, do a
factory reset and then restore things like photos and text
messages, but install the apps that I wanted from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed like Smart Switch was a good tool for this. One hiccup
was that the program doesn’t appear to have a way to do a partial
restore. I had backed up everything on my phone and, when I
did the restore, it put everything back the way it had been. Great
verification of the back-up/restore process but not exactly what I
wanted in this instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to do a new backup with only the data items that I wanted to
restore selected in the preferences. After a second factory reset,
this time the restore did exactly what I wanted and I set about
restoring the apps I use often from my Google Play store library.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><summary type="html">Samsung Smart Switch is a tool that will backup your phone and transfer the data to a new Samsung phone. You also use it to backup your phone to your PC in case you need to restore it later.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NPM giving error EAI_AGAIN from Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)</title><link href="https://adrianba.net/2017/10/12/node-and-vpn/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NPM giving error EAI_AGAIN from Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)" /><published>2017-10-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2012-10-12T10:44:00-07:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/2017/10/12/node-and-vpn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adrianba.net/2017/10/12/node-and-vpn/">&lt;p&gt;This morning I was experimenting with some demo code and when I tried to
install some packages from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt; I got the following network error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;request to https://registry.npmjs.org/XXX failed, reason: getaddrinfo EAI_AGAIN registry.npmjs.org:443
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;XXX&lt;/code&gt; was the name of the package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was running bash from Ubuntu using WSL but when I switched to a Windows command prompt and ran the Windows install of node/npm then it connected just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a little searching around but I discovered that this was most likely to do with the network proxy we have at Microsoft or some other quirk of the network configuration. We are currently testing a new on-demand VPN configuration, which had connected me to the corporate network even though I was actually attached directly. Disconnecting the VPN made things “just work” so I guess there was some kind of networking loop that Windows native networking could figure out since it has my login credentials whereas Ubuntu couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;EAI_AGAIN&lt;/code&gt; error is a transient failure and is probably related to something you can fix about your network config.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><summary type="html">This morning I was experimenting with some demo code and when I tried to install some packages from npm I got the following network error:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Microsoft Flow to publish medium.com recommendations</title><link href="https://adrianba.net/2016/09/24/using-microsoft-flow-to-publish-medium-com-recommendations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Microsoft Flow to publish medium.com recommendations" /><published>2016-09-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-24T12:01:17-07:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/2016/09/24/using-microsoft-flow-to-publish-medium-com-recommendations</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adrianba.net/2016/09/24/using-microsoft-flow-to-publish-medium-com-recommendations/">&lt;p&gt;Like a growing number of people, I read a lot of content on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/&quot;&gt;medium.com&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to find a way to share the posts that I find most interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of weeks I’ve been playing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://flow.microsoft.com/&quot;&gt;Microsoft Flow&lt;/a&gt;, which allows you to create automated workflows between different apps and services. I’m not on the Flow team - I just think the service is interesting, especially now that it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://flow.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/available-for-everyone/&quot;&gt;available for everyone&lt;/a&gt; to use. It reminds me of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yahoo!_Pipes&quot;&gt;Yahoo Pipes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/uploads/2016/09/microsoft-flow.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/uploads/2016/09/microsoft-flow-300x284.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Microsoft Flow editor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweeting out recommended reading from medium.com is very simple using Flow. Medium has an RSS feed with a list of your recommendations at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://medium.com/feed/@_your-medium-id_/has-recommended&lt;/code&gt;. You can create a new Flow trigger from this RSS feed so that new entries cause the flow to run. By adding Post a tweet action, you can cause the new entry to post to Twitter. You can use data from the RSS field to populate the tweet. I post the URL and the title of the recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. I saved the flow with my Twitter credentials and now whenever I click the recommended button on a medium.com post, I tweet about it within a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><summary type="html">Like a growing number of people, I read a lot of content on medium.com. I wanted to find a way to share the posts that I find most interesting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Sublime Text as your git editor on Windows</title><link href="https://adrianba.net/2016/01/06/using-sublime-text-as-your-git-editor-on-windows/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Sublime Text as your git editor on Windows" /><published>2016-01-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-01-06T14:39:48-08:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/2016/01/06/using-sublime-text-as-your-git-editor-on-windows</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adrianba.net/2016/01/06/using-sublime-text-as-your-git-editor-on-windows/">&lt;p&gt;Many git commands require using an editor including &lt;a href=&quot;http://chris.beams.io/posts/git-commit/&quot;&gt;writing good commit messages&lt;/a&gt;. I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/3&quot;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; as my default text editor and I wanted to make sure git launched Sublime Text appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Windows, the sublime_text.exe program has a couple of command line options that help here. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; option causes a new editing window to be created and the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; option tells Sublime Text to wait until you close the window before returning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, the Sublime Text 3 installer puts everything into “C:\Program Files\Sublime Text 3”. The spaces in the folder names makes the git command to configure the editor slightly trickier than normal. The following command sets up the global editor for git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git config --global core.editor &quot;\&quot;C:\Program Files\Sublime Text 3\sublime_text.exe\&quot; -n -w&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check that the configuration has been correctly stored with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git config --global -l&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><summary type="html">Many git commands require using an editor including writing good commit messages. I use Sublime Text as my default text editor and I wanted to make sure git launched Sublime Text appropriately.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MDI to TIFF converter</title><link href="https://adrianba.net/2015/12/20/mdi-to-tiff-converter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MDI to TIFF converter" /><published>2015-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2015-12-20T11:40:07-08:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/2015/12/20/mdi-to-tiff-converter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adrianba.net/2015/12/20/mdi-to-tiff-converter/">&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Office Document Imaging (MODI) was part of Office up to Office 2007. It allowed you to scan multipage documents into .MDI files. MODI was deprecated and removed from Office 2010 and with a modern installation of Windows and Office there is no native support for .MDI files. If you have these files archived then you will need to convert them to another format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;_MDI to TIFF File Converter is a command line tool, which allows you to convert one or more MDI files to TIFF. MDI is a proprietary file format of MODI (Microsoft Office Document Imaging), which was deprecated as part of Office 2010. This conversion tool will allow you to view MDI files after they are converted to TIFF. TIFF files may be viewed using a variety of image viewing programs, such as the Windows Fax and Image Viewer._&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=30328&quot;&gt;MDI to TIFF File Converter&lt;/a&gt; is a command line tool for converting old .MDI files to modern multipage TIFF files, which can be viewed with built-in tools like Windows Photo Viewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the converter from a command line prompt as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mdi2tif -source _myfile_.mdi -log output.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will produce the following output:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;`Converting MDI file myfile.mdi
Writing results file output.txt…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversion completed.
Files with errors: [0/1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See output.txt for more details. `&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;myfile&lt;/em&gt;.mdi will be converted to &lt;em&gt;myfile&lt;/em&gt;.tif.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><summary type="html">Microsoft Office Document Imaging (MODI) was part of Office up to Office 2007. It allowed you to scan multipage documents into .MDI files. MODI was deprecated and removed from Office 2010 and with a modern installation of Windows and Office there is no native support for .MDI files. If you have these files archived then you will need to convert them to another format.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using DVI monitors with the new Surface Dock</title><link href="https://adrianba.net/2015/12/05/using-dvi-monitors-with-the-new-surface-dock/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using DVI monitors with the new Surface Dock" /><published>2015-12-05T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2015-12-05T22:46:56-08:00</updated><id>https://adrianba.net/2015/12/05/using-dvi-monitors-with-the-new-surface-dock</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adrianba.net/2015/12/05/using-dvi-monitors-with-the-new-surface-dock/">&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/surface/en-us/accessories/surface-dock&quot;&gt;Surface Dock&lt;/a&gt; from Microsoft has two &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mini_DisplayPort&quot;&gt;mini-DisplayPort&lt;/a&gt; outputs that can be used to connect a Surface Book, Surface Pro 3, or Surface Pro 4 to two external monitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes it possible to connect to VGA, DVI, or HDMI devices with the use of an adapter. However, to work with a DVI input you must use an active DVI adapter. Using a passive DVI cable will not work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00OQX9526/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00OQX9526&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sailaboaacata-20&amp;amp;linkId=BVIV3PZJL3UDUQLA&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B00OQX9526&amp;amp;Format=_SL160_&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=sailaboaacata-20&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=sailaboaacata-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00OQX9526&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;I tried using a passive DVI cable to connect to my Dell IN2020M monitors. This results in the monitor displaying an error message: “&lt;em&gt;The current input timing is not supported by the monitor display. Please change your input timing to 1600x900@60Hz or any other monitor listed timing as per the monitor specifications.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00OQX9526/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00OQX9526&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=sailaboaacata-20&amp;amp;linkId=4NOERCYLKA3JVYE6&quot;&gt;gofanco Gold Plated Mini Displayport to DVI Active Converter&lt;/a&gt; on Amazon works well with the Surface Dock and I am now driving my two monitors with a good stable image.&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=sailaboaacata-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00OQX9526&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adrian Bateman</name></author><summary type="html">The new Surface Dock from Microsoft has two mini-DisplayPort outputs that can be used to connect a Surface Book, Surface Pro 3, or Surface Pro 4 to two external monitors.</summary></entry></feed>